Register of the Allan E. Goodman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- 1975 INCREMENT, 1956-1974 (Boxes 38-108)
  - SUBJECT FILE, 1956-1974 (Boxes 52-96)
    - France
      - Local government, Kesselman, Mark, "Research Perspectives in Comparative Local Politics: Reflections on Theory and Notes on the French Case,", 1971
    - Germany, East, Foreign policy
    - Ghana
    - Greeks in the U.S.
    - Guatemala
      - Insurgency
      - Politics, Solomon, Robert L.
        - "The Politics of Exile: Views of the Guatemalan Experience,", 1968
        - "The Politics of Exile in Guatemala: A Study in Political Pathology,", 1968
    - Ho Chi Minh, "Prison Diary,", 1967
    - Hoa Hao sect
    - Hong Kong
    - Huong, Tran Van
    - India
      - Commerce
        - General
        - Timberg, Thomas A., "Marwari Merchant Migration: A Survey and Discussion of the Relevance of Theory,", 1973
      - Economy
      - Elections
      - Labor
      - Politics
    - Indians in Southeast Asia
    - Indonesia (Box 56)
      - Communism
      - Defense policy
      - Economy
      - Education
      - Foreign policy
      - Government
      - Migration
        - General
        - "A Study of Migration in Indonesia: A Proposal,", 1972
      - Military in politics
        - General
        - Pauker, G. J., "The Role of the Military in Indonesia,", 1960
      - Miscellaneous
      - National development planning
        - General
        - Parker, Harrison, "Planning and Monitoring: Decentralized Development Programs in Indonesia,", 1972
        - Seminar on Science and Technology in Indonesian Development, Center for Developmental Change, University of Kentucky, Lexington, 1967 May 21-27
        - Research proposals
      - Nationalism
      - Politics
        - General
        - Pauker, Guy J.
          - "After Turmoil, the Upward Climb,", 1968
          - "Indonesia: The Age of Reason?,", 1968
          - "The Politics of Instability,", 1968
      - Population
      - Press
      - Religion
      - Rural Development
        - General
        - Pauker, Guy J., "Political Consequences of Rural Development Programs in Indonesia,", 1967
      - Taxation
    - Insurgency
      - General
      - Schaffer, Marvin B., "Lanchester Models of Guerilla Engagements,", 1967
      - Bibliography
    - International development assistance (Box 57)
    - International economic relations
      - General
      - Horvath, Janos and Patricia Burke Horvath, "The Widening Gap: Fact or Phantom?,", 1974
    - International relations
      - General
      - Wolf, Charles, Jr., "Asian Futures,", 1968
      - Bibliography
    - Israel, military in politics
    - Italians in the U.S.
    - Jackson, Senator Henry M.
    - Jakarta, Indonesia
    - Japan
      - Defense policy
        - General
        - Weinstein, Martin E., "Japan's Defense Policy and and the Self-Defense Forces,", 1972
      - Foreign aid
      - Foreign aid to South Korea
      - Foreign economic relations
        - General
        - Kahn, Herman and Max Singer, "Japan in the 1970's,"
        - Onishi, Akira, "Japanese Interests in Southeast Asia: A Japanese View,", 1970
      - Foreign policy
        - General
        - Murakamy, Kazuo, "On the American-Soviet-Chinese Triangular Power Relations and Japan's Role in Asia in the 1970's"
      - History
      - Miscellaneous
      - National development planning
      - Politics
    - Japan Socialist Party. Langer, Paul F. and Daniel I. Okomoto, "The Japan Socialist Party and Japanese National Security,", 1968
    - Japanese in the U.S.
    - Jews in the U.S.S.R.
    - Juvenile delinquency
      - General
      - General (Box 58)
      - Africa, U.N. Economic Commission for Africa, "Rapid Social Change and Juvenile Delinquency in Africa,", 1964
      - Latin America
      - North America
      - Statistics
        - General
        - Belgium
        - Canada
        - Colombia
        - France
        - Germany, West
        - Ghana
        - Great Britain
        - Greece
        - Ireland
        - Israel
        - Japan
        - Mexico
        - Norway
        - Portugal
        - Sweden
        - Syria
        - U.S.
          - General
          - California
        - Vietnam, South
    - Kenya
      - Communications
      - Economy
      - Education
      - Government
      - Justice
      - Migration
      - Politics
      - Population
      - Voluntary associations
    - Khiem, Tran Thien
    - Khmer Rouge, Pond, Elizabeth, "Portrait of a Revolutionary,", 1970
    - Kissinger, Henry A.
    - Korea
      - General
      - Armistice talks
      - History
    - Korea, North (Box 59)
    - Korea, South
      - Constitutions
      - Defense policy
      - Economy
      - Government
      - Internal dissension
      - Miscellaneous
      - National development planning
        - General
        - Lee, Hahn-Been, "A Case of Institution Building on the Foundation of a University Technical Assistance Contract,", 1968
      - Politics
      - Relations with North Korea
    - Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
    - Kurds
    - Ky, Ha Thuc
    - Ky, Nguyen Cao
    - Laos
      - Agriculture
      - History, Fredman, H. B., "Laos in Strategic Perspective,", 1961
      - Literacy, Wilder, Bernard, "The Literacy Skills of the Underschooled Literate Lao,", 1971
      - National development planning
        - General
        - Laos Commission General of the Plan, "Foreign Assistance for the Development of Laos,", 1969
      - Politics
    - Latin America
      - Censorship
      - Insurgency
      - Military in politics
      - National development planning
      - Politics
      - Radicalism, Einaudi, Luigi R., "Latin American Student Radicalism: A Different Type of Struggle,", 1968
    - Law, Nunez, Richard, "Law and Economic Development,", undated
    - Lee Kuan Yew
    - Legislatures
    - Limited wars
    - Loc, Nguyen Van
    - Local Government
      - General
      - Kuroda, Yasumasa, "A Comparative Study of Local Politics in Asia: A Review and Methodological Suggestions,", 1970
      - Long, Norton E., "Inventorying the Human Condition and the Study of Comparative Local Government,", 1970
    - Machiavelli, Niccolo
    - Malaysia
      - Bibliography
        - General
        - "A Preliminary Bibliography for the Study of Socio-Cultural Pluralism and Mobilization in West Malaysia,", undated
      - Economy (Box 60)
      - Elections
      - Foreign policy
      - Miscellaneous
      - National development planning
        - General
        - Malaysia Federal Department of Town and Country Planning, "Looking Ahead: Selangor, 1982,", undated
      - Nationalism
      - Politics
      - Population
      - Rural development
        - General
        - Chee, Stephen, "Rural Development and Development Administration in Malaysia,", 1974
        - Ness, Gayl D., "Models of Rural Development Administration: The Malaysian Ministry for Rural Development,", 1967
    - Mali, Coups
    - Malnutrition
    - Mao Tse-tung
    - Marcos, Ferdinand E.
    - Mekong River development
      - Hanna, Willard A., "The Rediscoveries of the Mekong, Part I: Mekongologues and Mekongophiles,", 1970
      - Ingersoll, Jasper, "Detailed Research Design,", 1967
      - Macaspac, Isidro S., "Economic and Social Research for Lower Mekong Basin Development: Some Considerations for the Design of Future Programs,", 1966
      - Mekong Development Panel Meeting, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Cornell University Ithaca, New York, 1974 March 22-24
      - Mekong Development Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York City, 1972 August 29-31
      - Philip, Nicholas, "The Mekong as a Resource: For South Vietnam, for Southeast Asia,", 1970
    - Meo tribe
    - Micronesia
    - Middle East
    - Migration and national development
    - Military in politics
    - Military-industrial complex
    - Minh, General Duong Van ("Big")
    - Miscellaneous
    - Mozambique, insurgency
    - Multilateral force
    - National development and demographic change
      - General
      - Morrison, Peter A., "How Population Movements Shape National Growth,", 1973
      - Bibliography
    - National development planning
      - General
      - Cummings, Harry, "Regional and Urban Development in a National Setting: Approaches to the Problem,", 1971
      - Kuznets, S., "Economic Growth of Small Nations,", undated (Box 61)
      - "The Literature of Institution Building,", undated
      - "Modernization and Development: Prospects for Intra-National Theory-Building and Research," American Political Science Association Seminar, New York City, 1972 March 24
      - Wynia, Gary W., "Political Participation and Development Policy-Making: Latitudes and Disciplines in Five Central American Systems,", 1970
      - Bibliography
        - General
        - Rodwin, Lloyd and Alex Ganz, comp., "Metropolitan and Regional Planning in Developing Countries,", 1969
    - National development planning and international relations
    - National interest
    - Nepal
    - New Zealand, foreign policy
    - Nicaragua, elections
    - Nigeria
      - Civil War
      - National development planning
    - Nixon, Richard M.
    - Nixon Doctrine
      - General
      - Johnson, Robert H., "The Nixon Doctrine and the New Policy Environment,", undated
    - North American Air Defense Command
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization
    - Nuclear submarines
    - Okinawa
    - Pakistan
      - Agriculture
      - Relief
    - Palestinian guerrillas
    - Panama, military in politics
    - Panama Canal
    - Paris peace talks
      - General
      - Blum, James, "Analysis of and Partial Index to the Chronology of September 17, 1970,"
      - NLF views
      - North Vietnamese views
      - South Vietnamese views
      - U.S. views
    - Parliamentary systems
    - Pathet Lao, Langer, Paul F., "Comments on Bernard Fall's The Pathet Lao: A 'Liberation' Party,", 1968
    - Patron-client political structures
      - General
      - Scott, James C., "Patron-Client Politics and Political Change,", 1970
    - Paul VI, Pope
    - Peace
    - Peru
      - Military in politics
        - General
        - Einaudi, Luigi R., "The Peruvian Military: A Summary Political Analysis,", 1969
      - Politics
    - Philippines (Box 62)
      - Agriculture
        - General
        - Houston, Charles O., "An Augenblick at the Philippine Rice Industry,", 1967
      - Bibliography
      - Defense policy
      - Economy
      - Insurgency
        - Hukbalahap
          - General
          - Mitchell, Edward J., "The Huk Rebellion in the Philippines: An Econometric Study,", 1968
        - Moslem
      - Legislature
      - Miscellaneous
      - National development planning
      - Politics
        - General
        - Klitgaard, Robert E., "Martial Law in the Philippines,", 1972
        - Laquian, Aprodicio A., "Martial Law in the Philippines to Date,", 1974
      - Rural development, Philippine-American Rural Development Workshop, Los Banos, Philippine Islands, 1966 June 6-17
    - Phoenix operation
    - Political opposition
    - Political participation
    - Political pressure groups
    - Political stability
    - Politics
      - General
      - Braibanti, Ralph, "The Policy Sciences and a General Theory of Political Change,", 1971
      - Brewer, Garry D., "A Policy Approach to the Study of Political Development and Change,", 1972
    - Population density
    - Population growth
      - General
      - Montgomery, John D., "A Strategy for Analyzing the Effects of Rapid Population Growth on the Administration of Public Service,", 1972
    - Powell, Representative Adam Clayton, Jr.
    - Power
      - Aberbach, Joel D., "Power and Consciousness: A Comparative Analysis,", 1973
      - Bell, David V. J.
        - "Power, Influence, and Authority: An Analysis,", undated
        - "Power, Influence, and Authority: Insights Derived from Decision Theory,", undated
    - Press summaries, South Vietnamese, Saigon Press Review of Vietnamese and Chinese Dailies, 1971-1972 (Box 63)
    - Property tax assessment (Box 64)
    - Puerto Ricans in the U.S.
    - Republican Party (U.S.), Constantini, Edmond and Kenneth H. Craik, "Competing Elites within a Political Party: A Study of Republican Leadership,", undated
    - Revolutionaries
      - General
      - Denton, Frank and Constantine Menges, "A Preliminary Proposal for a Comparative Study of Revolutionaries,", 1967
    - Revolutions
      - Bell, David V. J.
        - "Classical Theories of Resistance and Revolution,", 1971
        - "Justice and Injustice: The Rationale of Resistance,", 1972
        - "Some Reflections on the Comparison between the Vietnamese and American 'Revolutions',", 1968
      - Ellsberg, Daniel, "Violent Politics: The Role of Popular Attitudes and Action in Rebellion and Counter-Rebellion,", 1968
      - Leites, Nathan and Charles Wolf, Jr.
        - "Rebellion and Authority: An Analytic Essay on Insurgent Conflicts,", 1968
        - "Rebellion and Authority: Myths and Realities Reconsidered,", 1966
      - Mitchell, Edward J., "Relating Rebellion to the Environment: An Econometric Approach, 1967
      - Shubs, Peter, "Revolutionary Symbology: Comparative Case Studies of the American and Indian Independence Movements,", 1969
    - Rogers, William P.
    - Roy, M. N.
    - Rural development
      - General
      - Research proposals
    - Saigon, South Vietnam
      - History
      - Migration
        - Code Book
        - Questionnaires (Box 65-73)
    - Saudi Arabia, insurgency (Box 74)
    - Service, John Stewart
    - Sierra Leone, coups
    - Sikkim
    - Singapore
      - Economy
      - Miscellaneous
      - National development planning
      - Politics
      - Relations with Great Britain
    - Sino-Soviet dispute
    - Social fragmentation
    - Social science research
    - Solzhenitsyn, Alexander
    - Somaliland, French
    - South Africa and the U.S. Paton, Alan, speech to the Associated Harvard Alumni, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1971 June 17
    - South Asia. Wilcox, Wayne, "Alternative Futures for South Asia,", 1968
    - Southeast Asia
      - Anthropology
      - Bibliography
      - Culture
      - Economy
      - Foreign relations
      - Geography
      - Insurgency
      - Labor
        - Ad hoc Seminar on Labor Strategies, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Baguio, Philippine Islands, 1973 August 21-24
        - Conference on Manpower Problems in East and Southeast Asia, Singapore, 1971 May 22-28
      - Maps
      - National development planning
        - General
        - Development Administration Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Singapore, 1973 July 23-27
        - Development Administration Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Durham, New Hampshire, 1970 May 1-2
        - Development Administration Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Warrenton, Virginia, 1968 September 7-8
        - Fryer, Donald W., "National Development Plans and the Budget: Public Sector Resources for Urbanization,", 1969 (Box 75)
        - Vietnam, Laos, Khmer Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York City, 1974 January 14-16
        - Wolf, Charles, Jr., "National Priorities and Development Strategies in Southeast Asia,", 1965
      - Politics
        - General
        - Enloe, Cynthia H., "Development Viewed from the Palace: Political Scientists Look at Southeast Asian Ethnic Politics,", 1972
        - Gordon, Bernard K., "Regions and Regionalism,", 1967
        - Guyot, James F., "Political Succession and Political Development in Burma and Malaysia,", 1969
        - Heine-Geldern, Robert, "Conceptions of State and Kingship in Southeast Asia,", 1956
        - Simon, Sheldon W., "Assessing Peking's Perception of Southeast Asia: A Research Approach,", 1967
        - Solomon, Robert L., "Aspects of State, Kingship and Succession in Southeast Asia,", 1970
      - Population
        - General
        - Population Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Elkridge, Maryland, 1972 April 6-8
      - Religion
      - Rural development
        - Rural Development Panel Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York City, 1973 July 9-11
        - Rural Development Seminar, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, New York City, 1967 February 1-2
      - Social science research
      - Stability
    - Southeast Asia Treaty Organization
      - General
      - Vargas, Lieutenant General Jesus M., "Report on SEATO, 1966-1967,"
    - Soviet-American detente
      - General
      - Economic aspects
    - Soviet-American detente and dissension in the U.S.S.R.
    - Soviet-American detente and the Middle East
    - Sri Lanka
      - General
      - Politics
    - Statistics. Strauch, Ralph, "Some Thoughts on the Use and Misuse of Statistical Inference,", 1968
    - Strategic Arms Limitation Talks
      - General
      - Jackson, Senator Henry M., "Credible Deterrence in a SALT II Environment,", 1972
    - Student radical movements
    - Sudan, insurgency
    - Suharto
    - Systems analysis (Box 76)
      - General
      - Enthoven, Alain C.
        - "Economic Analysis in the Department of Defense,", 1962
        - "Operations Research at the National Policy Level,", 1962
        - "Two Lectures on the Art of Military Operations Research,", 1960
      - Moore, Jackie and Douglas A. Lawhorn, "Cost Reasonableness and Management Audits: A Concept,", undated
    - Taiwan, miscellaneous
    - Taylor, Theodore B.
    - Tenure, academic
    - Terrorism
    - Thailand
      - General
        - General
        - Viravan, Amnuay, "Economic Policy and Political Structures in Thailand,", 1967
        - Wilson, David A., "Thailand: 1962,"
      - Agriculture
      - Bibliography
      - Communist propaganda
      - Constitutions
      - Coup, 1973 October
      - Economy
      - Elections
      - Foreign policy
        - General
        - Gurtov, Melvin, "The Thai View of Asia: Comments by Foreign Minister Thanat Khoman,", 1967
      - Insurgency
        - General
        - Phillips, H. P. and D. A. Wilson, "Certain Effects of Culture and Social Organization on Internal Security in Thailand,", 1964
      - Lawyers
      - Legislators
      - Maps
      - National development planning
        - General
        - Thailand National Economic Development Board, "Summary of the Second Five-Year Plan (1967-1971),", 1966
      - Politics
      - Rural development
        - General
        - Wilson, David and Gayl D. Ness, "Rural Development in Thailand: Research Strategies,", 1966
    - Thanh, Tran Chanh (Box 77)
    - Thieu, Nguyen Van
    - Third Force
    - Togo, Coups
    - Tuong, Cao Van
    - U.S.
      - Antiwar movement
        - General
        - Shriver, Sargent, "The Quest for Peace,", 1972
        - Woodcock, Leonard, "Give Peace a Chance,", 1971
        - National Committee for a Political Settlement in Vietnam/Negotiation Now!
      - Bureaucracy
      - Central Intelligence Agency
      - Congress
        - General
        - Responsiveness to constituents
        - Role in foreign policy formulation
      - Defense budget
      - Defense policy
        - General
        - Barnet, Richard, "The National Security Bureaucracy and Military Intervention,", 1968 (Box 78)
        - Brown, Seyom, "Information for National Security Policy: Scope of Inquiry,", 1968
        - Bibliography
        - Counterinsurgency
          - Brown, David E., "The Politics of Counterinsurgency,", 1970
          - Reinhardt, G. C., "Guerilla-Combat, Strategy and Deterrence in Southeast Asia,", 1964
          - U.S. Naval War College School of Naval Command and Staff, "Readings in Counterinsurgency, 1970-1971: Part II,"
        - Satire. Brennan, D. G., "Project Turnabout: An Effective ICBM Defense,", 1970
        - Study and teaching
          - National Security Education Seminar, Colorado College, Colorado Springs, "Report of the Committee on the Teaching of National Security Policy", 1972, June 15-July 14
          - National Security Education Seminar, Colorado College, Colorado Springs, 1973 June 18-July 13
            - General
            - "Final Report"
            - "Report of Committee on Teaching"
          - "National Security Studies in an Age of Detente," regional seminar, Clark University, Worcester, Massachusetts, 1974 February 22-23
          - U.S. Naval War College, lecture program, 1971
      - Defense policy and foreign policy, Haley, P. E., "On the Relationship between Policy and Strategy,", undated
      - Defense policy and the academic community
      - Department of Defense, "Legislative History of the Department of Defense,", undated
      - Education
      - Elections, 1960, presidential, 1960 September 26
        Contains a transcript from CBS-Chicago of the first joint radio television broadcast with Senator John F. Kennedy and Vice President Richard M. Nixon.
      - Embassy, Saigon, personnel, 1968
      - Foreign aid
        - General
        - Dye, Richard W., "The United States and Asia: The Changing Environment for Aid,", 1970
        - Ziegler, Ronald, statement at press conference, the White House, Washington, D.C., 1971 October 30
      - Foreign aid for urban development planning (Box 79)
        - Agency for International Development
          - General
          - U.S. Agency for International Development Bureau for Technical Assistance Urban Development Staff
            - "Preliminary Report of the Results of Consultation on Identifying Critical Urban Development Problems,", 1971
            - "A Summary Report of A.I.D. Technical Assistance for Urban Development: A Study of Agency Experience, 1949-1970,", 1971
            - "Towards a Definition of Urban Development Policy,", 1970
        - Peace Corps. Mecartney, Bruce W., "Peace Corps Programs in Urban Affairs and Development Planning,", undated
      - Foreign aid to Cambodia
      - Foreign aid to Greece
      - Foreign aid to Laos
        - General
        - Mendenhall, Joseph A., "United States Aid to Laos,", 1966
        - "United States Aid to Laos,", undated
      - Foreign cultural relations
      - Foreign economic relations
      - Foreign policy
        - General
        - Horton, Captain Frank B., III, "The Possibility of Programming U.S. Foreign Operations,", 1967
        - Moore, David W., "Foreign Policy and Empirical Democratic Theory,", undated
        - Simpson, Lieutenant Commander B. M., III, "The Evaluation of U.S. Post-War Foreign Policy,", 1971
        - "U.S. Department of State Scholar-Diplomat Seminars,", 1971
      - Foreign policy and the academic community
        - General
        - George, Alexander L., "Bridging the 'Gap' between Scholarly Research and Policy-Makers: The Problem of Theory and Action,", 1968
      - Foreign policy in Africa
      - Foreign policy in Asia
      - Foreign policy in Latin America
      - Foreign policy in South Asia
      - Foreign policy in Southeast Asia (Box 80)
        - General
        - Bundy, William P., speech to the Commonwealth Club of California, San Francisco, 1967 January 20
        - Gurtov, Melvin, "United States Policy in Southeast Asia,", 1968
        - Gurtov, Melvin and Daniel I. Okimoto, "United States Policy in Southeast Asia after Vietnam,", 1968
        - Malmgren, H. B., "The United States, the New Pacific Basin Era and Vietnam,", undated
        - Pauker, Guy J.
          - "The Future Role of the United States in Asia and the Pacific,", 1968
          - "The War in Vietnam and the Role of the United States in the Future Power Balance of Asia,", 1967
        - U.S. Department of State Scholar-Diplomat Seminar for East Asian Affairs, Washington, D.C., 1970 December 14-18
      - Foreign policy in Vietnam
        - General
        - Bundy, William P., speech to the National Student Association, 1968 August 15